dward Esteban León Solar

SYSTEMS ENGINEER

[DEVELOPER OF WEB APPLICATIONS]

ABSTRACT

Graduated in March 2014 with the degree of Systems Engineer, I started working at CANTV as a developer of Web applications. For the year 2015 I completed the Diploma in Business Intelligence at the Central University of Venezuela. I have more than four years of experience in Web development with PHP.

I enjoy working on Open Source projects during my free time. My goals are aimed at success; I am constant, self-taught and collaborative.

SKILLS

Programming languages: Php, Js, Java, Python, C++, SQL, PLSQL.

Databases: PostgreSql, Mysql, Oracle.

Frameworks: Yii Framework, Codeigniter, Laravel, Bootstrap, Angular.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JQUERY, JSON, AJAX, GIT, SVN, Pentaho DI, WordPress, API.

Design patterns: MVC, DDD.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



FREELANCE www.edwardleon.com.ve

Caracas, Venezuela

01 / 2016 - Present

Software Developer

Development of customized software and leadership of development teams.



Barcelona, España (Remote)

05 / 2016 - 07 / 2018 (2 years and 2 months)

Web developer

Analysis and development of web solutions with Codeigniter Framework, Laravel Framework, Bootstrap Framework and Mysql. Corrective and evolutionary systems maintenance.

Reference: Sys.E. Joisamar Garcia. Web developer. Tel: +58 0424-930.60.63



COMPAÑÍA ANÓNIMA NACIONAL **TELÉFONOS DE VENEZUELA**

Caracas, Venezuela

05 / 2014 - 12 / 2015 (1 year and 7 months)

www.cantv.net

Information Technology Specialist

Analysis and development of web solutions with YII Framework and PostgreSQL. Development of stored procedures with plpgsql. Development of shellscript with bash. Management of platforms for installation of web applications. Administration of web servers with Apache.

Reference: Sys.E. José Hamilton. Team lead. Tel: +58 0416-805.22.93



PERSONAL INFORMATION

DNI: V-19.201.202 BD: 1989 / 11 / 15

CONTACT

eleonsolar@gmail.com

(+58) (0426) 821.94.28 (+58) (0212) 814.39.84 Skype: eleonsolar

PORTFOLIO

www.edwardleon.com.ve

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native) English (Intermidiate)

Updated to date: October 2018

EDUCATION

DIPLOMA IN BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE

Caracas-Venezuela 2015

Universidad Central de Venezuela (U.C.V)

SYSTEMS ENGINEER Caracas-Venezuela 2008-2014

Universidad Nacional Experimental Politécnica de la Fuerza Armada Nacional (U.N.E.F.A)

ADDITIONAL FORMATIONS

- C++ SoloLearn, January 2018, Certified URL: https://www.sololearn.com/Profile/3662276/
- Cloud Computing Activate con Google, March 2017, Certified URL:

https://www.dropbox.com/s/0ixk6d66tdam1ix/Cloud computing.pdf?dl=0

- Python 3 SoloLearn, February 2017, Certified URL: https://www.sololearn.com/Profile/3662276/
- Wordpress Nivel 1 y Nivel 2 Uneweb Instituto de Nuevas Tecnologías, Caracas February 2017.
- JAVA Specialist SE 8 Instituto Educativo Softrain, Caracas March July 2016.
- Mysql for beginners Udemy, Mayo 2016, Certified URL: http://ude.my/UC-AAIDTZHH
- Programming language PHP Academia de Software Libre, Caracas September 2013.
- Technical Support GNU/Linux Academia de Software Libre, Caracas June 2013.
- Community Facilitator in Free Information Technologies Centro Nacional de Tecnologías de Información, Caracas March 2013.
- **Diagramming workshop with UML and StarUML** Universidad Nacional Experimental Politécnica de la Fuerza Armada Nacional, Caracas June 2012.
- Network Installer Specialist Instituto de Capacitación Técnica Keys Caracas 2010-2011.

Updated to date: October 2018